George Fuermann "Texas and Houston" Collection
University of Houston Libraries
George Fuermann "Texas and Houston" Collection
1836-2001
Fuermann, George, 1918-
George M. Fuermann amassed this extensive collection of Texas and Houston historical materials during the period from 1950 - 1971. During this time he wrote a regular column, "Post Cards," on local history for the Houston Post and also authored ten volumes on the subject. The collection also includes much of George Fuermann's correspondence and manuscript material.
52 Boxes, 19 Series and 20 Linear Feet
1970-001
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Biographical Note
Born in Buffalo, New York on August 25, 1918, George Fuermann moved to Texas with his family in 1923. He died in Houston, at the age of 82, on January 20, 2001. He earned a journalism degree in 1941 from Texas A & M College, where he edited the student journal, “The Battalion.” Captain Fuermann received a Bronze Star during World War II, while serving the U. S. Army as a correspondent in the European Theater.
Mr. Fuermann's “Houston Post” career spanned 49 years. He began in 1946 as a general assignment reporter. His popular daily column, based on snippets of local history, “Post Card,” ran from 1950 to 1971. He continued as Editorial Page editor from 1971 to 1983 and as “Wine Talk” columnist from 1984 to 1995, when the “Houston Post” closed its doors. From 1996 to 1999, GEorge Fuermann wrote a wine column for a publication of the Rice Epicurean Markets.
George Fuermann authored approximately ten volumes. Additionally, he wrote numerous articles, forwards and other contributing texts. Among his best known books are Houston: Land of the Big Rich, 1951; Reluctant Empire, 1957; The Face of Houston, 1963 and Houston: The Once and Future City, 1971. For a complete list of his published volumes and other works to which he made a contribution, see sub-group II, box 1, folder 1.
In addition to his writing, Mr. Fuermann, served the community as chair of the Municipal Arts Commission in 1965/66 and as a member until 1971. He also served as chair of the Houston Committee on Foreign Relations in 1977/78 and was a member of the American Bicentennial Commission. He founded two dining/social clubs, the “Seventh of April” in 1964 and “Cheap and Hungry” in 1985.
Scope and Contents
George Fuermann, 1918-2001, collected or produced published/printed materials; legal, financial and government documents; photographic materials; creative works; maps; works of art; artifacts; research files; correspondence and typescripts that comprise 41 boxes, approximately 17 linear feet, of regional history-related materials.
The collection is arranged in two sub-groups, consisting of a large collection of historical documentation, 1836-1988, in 40 boxes, as well as a limited set of Mr. Fuermann's correspondence, typescripts and other professional papers, 1952-2001, in 1 box.
Three appendices to this finding aid are available. Please contact Special Collections for more information.
Acquisition
Donated to the University of Houston by George Fuermann, in lots, from 1970 through 1983. Mr. Fuermann's family gave additional materials to the university, at the time of his death, in 2001.
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Subjects (Persons)
Fuermann, George, 1918-; Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964.; Webb, Walter Prescott, 1888-1963.
Subjects
Houston (Tex.); Houston (Tex.) -- Description and travel; Houston (Tex.) - History; Texas - Civilization; Texas - Maps; Texas Arts Houston; Texas History Republic 1835 1846; Texas History; Texians and the Texans; Texas History Republic 1835 1836; Houston (Tex.) Buildings, structures, etc. Pictorial works.; Houston (Tex.) Biography; Houston (Tex.) History Pictorial works; Houston (Tex.) Maps.
INVENTORY
- I. George Fuermann Historical Collection, 1836-1988, 8 Series, (A - H)
  - A. Printed Material, 1839-1979, 810 Items
    This series is contained in 4 boxes (plus the addition of a few oversized [OVS] items). It consists of published items that include promotional publications, serial publications, newspapers, clippings, broadsides and postcards. All materials chronicle the historical development of Texas and/or Houston.
    - Houston, Individuals and Organizations (Box 1)
      - Publications, About., 1913-1945; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Prospectus of Houston, Bay Shore & Texas City Traction Co., 1920; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mercantile Ephemera (Box 1)
      - Houston Packing Co., Large Postcards., [undated]; 6 items (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Assorted., 1860-1951; 26 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Houston (Box 1)
      - Periodical Articles., 1852-1866; 2 items (Box OVS 1, Folder 1-2)
      - Clipped Periodical Articles., 1901-1973; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Publications., 1891-1899; 5 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Publications., 1904-1965; 24 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Publication., 1928; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Harris County
      - Publication., 1888; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 3)
      - Publications., 1928-1950; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Texas
      - Clipped Cartoons., 1953-1957; 11 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Clipped Periodical Articles., 1839-1893; 6 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Clipped Periodical Articles., 1903-1939; 7 items (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Clipped Periodical Articles., 1945-1949; 7 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Clipped Periodical Articles., 1950-1955; 24 items (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Clipped Periodical Articles., 1955-1959; 25 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Clipped Periodical Articles., 1960-1967; 9 items (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Translated Article Typescripts., 1954-1958; 4 items (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Publications., 1873-1909; 13 items (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Newspaper Clippings., 1910-1965; 85 items (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Newspaper, Complete Editions., 1862-1896; 7 items (Box OVS 1, Folder 4-9)
      - Newspaper Special Editions/Sections., 1858-1864; 5 items (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Newspaper Special Editions/Sections., 1920-1937; 4 items (Box OVS 1, Folder 10-13)
      - Newspaper Special Editions/Sections., 1929; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Newspaper Single Leaves., 1862-1919; 10 items (Box OVS 1, Folder 14-20)
    - Broadsides
      - Assorted., 1845-1917; 8 items (Box 2, Folder 13-20)
      - Assorted., 1876-1979; 4 items (Box OVS 1, Folder 22-25)
    - Postcards
      (See Appendix I for Item List)
      - Agriculture., 1918-1927; 2 items (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
      - Animals., 1931-1950; 9 items (Box 3, Folder 3-11)
      - Texas Cities., 1873-1958; 306 items (Box 3, Folder 12-317)
      - Texas Cities., 1890-1957; 132 items (Box 4, Folder 1-132)
      - Cowboys., c. 1945; 5 items (Box 4, Folder 133-137)
      - Falcon Dam., c. 1953; 4 items (Box 4, Folder 138-141)
      - Humor., 1922-1950; 5 items (Box 4, Folder 142-146)
      - Assorted., 1895-1950; 8 items (Box 4, Folder 147-154)
      - Sunset Rail., 1908-1950; 11 items (Box 4, Folder 155-156)
      - Oil., 1931-1950; 2 items (Box 4, Folder 165-166)
      - Parks., 1933-1966; 14 items (Box 4, Folder 167-180)
      - Plants., 1901-1950; 4 items (Box 4, Folder 181-184)
      - Texans., 1906-1950; 9 items (Box 4, Folder 185-193)
      - U.S. Presidents., 1955; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 194)
  - B. Documents, 1836-1915, 630 Items
    Contained in 3 boxes, this series includes early Houston, as well as Republic, State and Confederate era, Texas materials. Houston documents range from “Public School” and “Board of Aldermen” to the office of “Scavenger” as well as most other existing departments. The bulk of items date from the last half of the Nineteenth Century. Signatures include those of Augustus C. Allen, Sam Houston, Anson Jones, Albert Sidney Johnston, Ashbel Smith and J. B. Magruder, among others.
    - Private—Business (Box 5)
      - Hermann, George H., 1878-1889; 8 items (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Jones, C. Anson., 1873-1889; 9 items (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Sharp, Walter and Hughes, Howard, Sr., 1908-1910; 3 items (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Westheimer, M.L., 1861-1894; 12 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Assorted Individuals and Companies., 1838-1903; 23 items (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Financial Institution's-Statements., 1901-1912; 32 items (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Charter of Early Navigation Company., 1873; 1 item (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - City of Houston (Box 5)
      - Assessor/Collector., 1874-1875; 5 items (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Assessor/Collector., 188?-1887; 2 items (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Assessor/Collector., 1895-1897; 6 items (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Bonds, Notes and Scrip., 1937-190?; 11 items (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Boards of Aldermen/City Council., [undated]; 2 items (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1868-1869; 2 items (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1871; 5 items (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1872; 7 items (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1873-1876; 11 items (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1879; 15 items (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1879; 11 items (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1880-1884; 6 items (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1886-1889; 9 items (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1890-1894; 7 items (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1895-1897; 9 items (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Board of Aldermen/City Council., 1901; 1 item (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Charters/Codes of Ordinance., 1847-1897; 12 items (Box 6, Folder 1-12)
      - Engineers Office., 1876; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Engineers Office., 1889; 3 items (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Engineers Office., 1890-1898; 9 items (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Engineers Office., 1899; 10 items (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Engineers Office., 1900-1901; 14 items (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Fire Department., 1879-1889; 8 items (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Fire Department., 1895-1896; 9 items (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Health Department., 1880; 6 items (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Invoices., 186?-1869; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Invoices., 1873-1876; 16 items (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Invoices., 1880-1889; 46 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Invoices., 1893-1898; 55 items (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Marshall's Office., 1869-1891; 6 items (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Mayor's Office., 1838; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Mayor's Office., 1875-1889; 6 items (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Mayor's Office., 1890-1899; 14 items (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Ordinances., 1879-1900; 7 items (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Police Department., 1880-1897; 16 items (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Public Schools., 1879; 9 items (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Public Schools., 1883-1887; 60 items (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Public Schools., 1892-1900; 23 items (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Public Schools/Diploma., 1915; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 26)
      - Railroad Company, City., 1861; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Scavenger., 1880; 3 items (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Secretary/Treasurer., 1874-1895; 15 items (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Streets and Bridges., 1869; 5 items (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Streets and Bridges., 1872-1889; 10 items (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Streets and Bridges., 1890-1905; 9 items (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Harris County (Box 7)
      - Assorted., 1859-1885; 7 items (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Marriage License., 1864; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Republic of Texas (Box 7)
      - Assorted., 1836-1846; 25 items (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Land Office Grant., 1846; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 27)
    - State of Texas, USA (Box 7)
      - Assorted., 1846-1860 [67]; 6 items (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - State of Texas, CSA (Box 7)
      - Assorted., 1862-1864; 7 items (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - State of Texas, USA (Box 7)
      - Assorted., 1874-1893; 7 items (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - C. Photographic Material, 1857-1969, 970 Items
    Over 800 still photographic images, in 23 boxes, document the history of Houston and her enterprise. The bulk of the series consists of photographic reproductions, although a few original prints are included. Broad subject categories of the “research photograph files” sub-series include notable people, places, buildings, streets, fires, bayous, parks and various industrial development, such as oil, construction and aviation. Other sub-series are “panoramas,” “aerial views” and “photographs used in publications.”
    - George Fuermann's Research Photograph Files
      (See Appendix II for Item List) Creator's Arrangement
      - People, Alphabetical., 1892-1963; 36 items (Box 8, Folder 1-36)
      - Places, Alphabetical., 1890-1912; 12 items (Box 8, Folder 37-48)
      - Identified Buildings., 1857-1964; 11 items (Box 8, Folder 49-59)
      - Identified Buildings., 1857-1964; 11 items (Box 9, Folder 60-120)
      - Identified Buildings., 1860-1970; 5items (Box 10, Folder 121-125)
      - Identified Streets., 1856-1960; 39 items (Box 10, Folder 126-165)
      - Unidentified Buildings., 1860-1920; 11 items (Box 10, Folder 163-172)
      - Aerial Views, Chronological., 1910-1920; 8items (Box 10, Folder 173-180)
      - Aerial Views, Chronological., 1927-1964; 48 items (Box 11, Folder 180-221)
      - Animals., 1954; 11 items (Box 11, Folder 222-232)
      - Aviation., undated; 17 items (Box 11-12, Folder 233-249)
      - Construction., 1955-1962; 9 items (Box 12, Folder 250-258)
      - Fire, 1912., 4 items (Box 12, Folder 259-262)
      - Photographs of Art and Maps., 1873-1959; 12 items (Box 12, Folder 263-273)
      - Assorted Images., 1873-1965; 21 items (Box 12, Folder 274-295)
      - Assorted Images., 1870-1960; 38 items (Box 13, Folder 296-334)
      - Newspaper Front Pages., 1910-1945; 11 items (Box 13, Folder 335-345)
      - Oil Wells., early 1900s; 14 items (Box 13, Folder 346-359)
      - Parks, Statues & Fountains., 1800- 1900; 25 items (Box 14, Folder 360-384)
      - Boats/Bayou/Channel/Port., 1910-1963; 27 items (Box 14, Folder 385-412)
      - Selected Mounted Duplicates., [undated]; 26 items (Box 15, Folder 413-434)
    - Photographs Used in Publications (Box 16)
      - Houston: The Feast Years (1962)., 1900-1962; 6 items (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - The Face of Houston (1963)., 1960s; 16 items (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - The New Year in Houston (1964)., 1864; 1 item (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Houston: The Once and Future City (1971)., 1876-1952; 10 items (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Panoramas (Box 17)
      - Rolled Tinted View of Montrose Addition., 191?; 1 item (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Black & White View of Downtown Houston, [framed]., 1909; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 27)
      - Black & White View of Downtown Houston., 1910; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 28)
    - Oversize Aerial Views (Box OVS 1)
      - Printed Aerial View of Texas Medical Center., 1969; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 30)
      - Printed Aerial View of Downtown Houston., 1968; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 31)
      - Aerial Night View of Houston., [1962]; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 32)
      - Lithograph of Aerial Night View of Houston., [undated]; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 33)
      - Printed Aerial View Houston Skyline., [1970s]; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 34)
      - Mounted Color Photograph of Rice Stadium., 1957; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 35)
      - Mounted Color Photograph of Houston Skyline at night., 1964; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 36)
      - Reproduction of Photograph of Houston's Main Street., 1876; 1 item (Box OVS 1, Folder 37)
    - Photographs Collected for Proposed Volume, This is Houston (Box 18-21)
      (See Appendix III for Item List) Creator's Arrangement
      - Assorted., [undated]; 268 items (Box 18-21, Folder 1-268)
      - Unidentified early 20th century snapshots and negatives, [undated] (Box 22)
      - Unidentified early 20th century snapshots and negatives, [undated] (Box 23)
  - D. Creative Works, 1844-1974., 234 Items
    Housed in 1 box, these Texas and Houston based materials include sheet music (cataloged), poetry, reprints and typescripts. The series excludes visual arts and the works of Mr. Fuermann.
    - Music (Box 24)
      - Sheet Music and Songbook., 1844-1928; 8 items [cataloged] (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Poetry (Box 24)
      - Assorted., 1937-1955; 4 items (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Inscribed Article Reprints (Box 24)
      - Historical Articles., 1935-1964; 4 items (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Texas and Her Constitutions (Box 24)
      Special Collections, cataloged; JK 4816.T47 1974
      - Typescript of Table of Contents., 1974; 2 items (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Typescript of Text, 1974; 22 segments (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Typescript of Text, 1974; 14 segments (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Photo List with Credits, 1974; 1 item (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Photo Images., 1974; 50 items (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Photo Images., 1974; 50 items (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Photo Images., 1974; 50 items (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Photo Images., 1974; 30 items (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - E. Maps, 1840-1960, 16 Items
    Nineteen original historical maps that chart the development of Houston, Harris County and Texas. These have all been separated from the collection and cataloged -- call numbers are indicated.
    - Catalog Records of Maps, 1974; 30 items (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Hand-Drafted Block Grid of Downtown Houston., c. 1910
        Call No.: G4034H8A15 1910.D68
      - Map of Houston Heights. [framed], c. 1914; 1 item
        Call No.: G4034.H8:2H4 G46 1890 .M35
      - Reproduction of 1884 Downtown Houston Grid., 1955; 1 item
        Call No.: G4034.H8 1884 C58 1955
      - Block Maps Called “Heart of Houston.”, c. 1960; 4 items
        Call No.: G4034.H8 A15 1960 H42
      - Map of Harris County showing land parcel divisions., 1912; 1 item
        Call No.: G4033.H35G46 1912 .R62
      - Gray's New Map of Brenham, Texas., 1884; 1 item
        Call No.: G4034.B74G46 1884 G73
      - Map of Palestine, Texas., 1884; 1 item
        Call No.: G4034.P34G46 1884 M36
      - Rand McNalley Railroad Map showing N.E. Texas., 1874; 1 item
        Call No.: G4061.P33 1874 .R35
      - Intl. & Great Northern RR-Map/Time Table. [framed], 1879; 1 item
        Call No.: G3861.P3 1879.M35
      - Map of South West by Southwestern Immigration., 1881; 1 item
        Call No.: G3991.P3 1881 S68
      - Railroad Map of Texas-East of the 100th Parallel., 1889; 1 item
        Call No.: G4031.P3 1884 R33
      - General Austin's Map of Texas, H.J. Tanner. [framed], 1840; 1 item
        Call No.: G4030 1840 .A8
      - County Map of Texas., 1860; 1 item
        Call No.: G4030 1860 .C68
      - J. DeCordova's Map of the State of Texas. [framed], 1866; 1 item
        Call No.: G4030 1866.C74
      - Gray's New Map of Texas and the Indian Territory., 1876; 1 item
        Call No.: G4030 1876 .G73
      - Galv., Harrisburg & San Ant. RR. Map. [framed], 1877; 1 item
        Call No.: G4031.P3 1900 .M35
      - Rand McNalley “Auto Trails” Map of Texas., 1923; 1 item
        Call No.: G4031.P2 1923 R35
      - County and Railroad Map of Texas by Houston Central RR., [undated]; 1 item (Box OVS 2, Folder 21)
      - J. H. Colton's Township Map of the Western U.S., 1853; 1 item
        Call No.: G4060 1853 .S6
  - F. Works of Art, 1873-1988, 146 Items
    Most of these artistic renderings are signed prints or original works and are contained in 1 oversize box. The bulk of the original works is in watercolor, wash, pen or pencil. Much of the work was done expressly for one or another of Mr. Fuermann's publications; by such artists as John Biggers, Lowell Collins and Buck Schiwetz.
    - Baxter, Norm (Box OVS 9)
      - Unsigned Prints., 1965-1970; 7 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 1)
    - Biggers, John (Box OVS 9)
      - Signed Original Sketches., 1966; 2 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 2)
      - Unsigned Original Sketch., 1969; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 3)
      - Inscribed, Signed and Dated Print., 1966; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 4)
      - Inscribed, Signed, Numbered and Dated Print., 1969; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 5)
    - Carlin, Robert (Box OVS 9)
      - Mounted and Framed Watercolor of Air Show., [undated]; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 6)
    - Cipriani,? (Box OVS 9)
      - Framed Oil Painting-Aerial View of Downtown Houston., [undated]; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 7)
    - Collins, Lowell (Box OVS 9)
      - Signed & Dated Watercolors., 1956-1958; 5 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 8)
      - Unsigned Watercolor., [undated]; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 9)
      - Unsigned Sketches with Black Wash., c. 1951; 6 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 10)
      - Signed and Dated Sketch., 1951; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 11)
      - Unsigned Sketches., [undated]; 2 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 12)
      - Signed, Dated & Numbered Woodcut Prints., 1962; 6 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 13)
      - Signed & Dated Artist Proof Woodcut Print., 1962; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 14)
      - Unsigned & Undated Woodcut Prints., c. 1962; 7 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 15)
    - Noe, David Gonzalez (Box OVS 9)
      - Child's Signed (on back) Sketch w/Watercolor., 1956; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 16)
    - Hinds, Bill (Box OVS 9)
      - Original Caricature of Mayor Louie Welch., 1971; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 17)
    - Kiesling,? (Box OVS 9)
      - Watercolor., 1956; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 18)
    - Klemola, Jeanette (Box OVS 9)
      - Series of Signed Pen and Ink Drawings., 1971; 33 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 19)
    - Lea, Tom (Box OVS 9)
      - Signed & Dated Print., 1964; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 20)
    - Preusser, Robert (Box OVS 9)
      - Signed Drawings Submitted for Building Project., 1954; 3 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 21)
    - Schiwetz, E. M. (Buck) (Box OVS 9)
      - Signed Mounted Pastel Drawing., 1954; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 22)
      - Signed Charcoal Drawing., [undated]; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 23)
      - Signed & Dated Color Pencil Sketch., 1931; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 24)
      - Signed & Dated Pencil Sketches., 1921-1928; 4 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 25)
      - Signed Pen & Ink Sketch., [undated]; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 26)
      - Signed “B” & Inscribed Pencil Sketch., [undated]; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 27)
      - Unsigned Pen & Ink w/Color Wash for Houston Mag., 1955; 3 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 28)
      - Signed Custom Prints., 1929; 3 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 29)
      - Commercial Prints in Portfolio., [undated]; 3 [of 12] items (Box OVS 9, Folder 30)
      - Complete Portfolio of Six Commercial Prints., [undated]; 6 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 31)
      - Assorted Commercial Prints., 1929-1955; 8 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 32)
    - Tackaberry, M.J. (Box OVS 9)
      - Pen & Ink Sketch., 1948; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 33)
    - Assorted Unidentifiable Original Work (Box OVS 9)
      - Unsigned Vintage Sketch “Prairie at Smith.”, [undated]; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 34)
      - Illegibly Signed Sketches-Female Nudes., 1967; 4 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 35)
      - Illegibly Signed Sketches Torn from Pad., 1987-1988; 4 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 36)
    - Assorted Unidentifiable Printed Work (Box OVS 9)
      - Vintage Black & White Engravings., ?-1873; 4 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 37)
      - Antique Color Bird Engravings., [undated]; 9 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 38)
      - Signed (w/initials M.C.) & Inscribed Woodcut Print., 1949; 1 item (Box OVS 9, Folder 39)
      - Initialed (J.K.R.) Pictorial Page Proofs for Esquire Article., 1955; 2 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 40)
      - Unsigned Commercial Black & White Prints., [undated]; 2 items (Box OVS 9, Folder 41)
  - G. Artifacts, 1891-1962, 12 Items
    This box of eleven items consists mostly of pins, medallions and ribbons as well as one City of Houston flag.
    - City of Houston Flag., [undated]; 1 item (Box 25, Folder 1)